Rakesh Jogani

Assistant Consultant Tata Consultancy Services Garima Park – Gandhinagar Gujarat

E: joganirakesh8225@gmail.com

M: +91 9662207750

Professional Profile

I am a confident, highly driven programmer analyst with experience in Microsoft.Net technology. I have a high level of involvement in the advancement of programming and adherence to best practice. Results - Oriented, Resourceful and Problem - Solving in large-scale software design and development. I provide excellent troubleshooting skills to analyse code and engineer well-researched, cost-effective, and responsive solutions.

- Over 10+ years of experience in Software Development performing various responsibilities.
- Strong understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and ability to work as a primary interface between Business Users and development team.
- Good grasp of operations, implementation, analytical, planning, communication, interpersonal and time management skills.
- Responsible for delivering the product/project to the client sufficing the quality and meeting deadlines (timeline) as planned.
- Hands on Experience on Angular CLI (Command line Interface).
- Experience in Agile/Scrum development.
- Willing to update my knowledge and learn new skills to perform efficiently.

Key Technical Skills

Technologies : ASP.NET C#, MVC, Web API, WCF, .Net Core Web API, Entity

Framework, LINQ

Web Technologies : Angular, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, Ajax, JSON,

Typescript, ES5/ES 6.

Database : MSSQL, Oracle

Version Control : TFS, DevOps, Octopus Deploy, SVN

Methodologies : Agile

Career Summary

Tata Consultancy Services, Assistant Consultant, Gandhinagar (Nov 2018 – Present)

Dev Information Technology Ltd, Sr. Software Developer, Ahmedabad (Apr 2016 – Nov 2018) (Dev information Technology Ltd acquired Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services' Software Department from April 2016)

Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services, Programmer Analyst, Ahmedabad (Dec 2013 – March 2016)

Verve System Private Limited, Software Developer, Ahmedabad (May 2011 – Dec 2013)

Key Projects

1. WKLS – ASM (Tata Consultancy Services, Jan 2020 - Present)

Wolters Kluwer Lien Solutions is web-based application used for filing UCC related filings like UCC1 and UCC3 filings. Manage the many internal and external applications which perform the fort end and back processing systems of filings.

ASP.NET C# | MVC | Angular | Web API | WCF | Web API | ASP.NET Core | Oracle

2. Windows Server Upgrade (Tata Consultancy Services, Nov 2018 to Jan 2020)

Upgrading the server from Windows server 2008 to Windows server 2016. We implement the CD (Continuous Deployment) process using Octopus deploy tool. Our scope is applying the config transformation, create octopus build definition and octopus variable creation setup of all applications.

Microsoft Technology | TFS | Octopus | Window Server 2016 | IIS

3. **Product Database** (Dev Information Technology Ltd & Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services,)
For a leading lighting products manufacturer in the UK and USA. The projects have 2 components

<u>PDB (Web Application)</u> - A product repository administration portal that integrates with NOP Commerce Portal, Microsoft Dynamics NAV ERP and other software/websites APIs.

ASP.NET 4.0 | C#.NET | MVC | MS SQL 2008 R2 | JQuery | AJAX | XML

<u>PDB Website (NOP Commerce)</u> - PDB website is a public website that contains product information for different countries. Each Country is showing the product information based on culture language. The customer can visit the website and inquire for products. There is also a mobile-friendly UI, people can also visit the website using a mobile device. PDB website totally manages dynamically. There is also managing products based on country.

NOPCommerce | MVC 5 | SQL Server 2012 | JQuery

a) <u>PDB Service APIs (WCF Service)</u> – WCF restful services and mainly consumed by NOP websites and others to pull the data from PDB to many websites.

ASP.NET 4.0 | C#.NET | WCF | MS SQL 2008 R2

4. FOSSLR (Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services)

The FOSSLR is a job portal that provides a new way for Job Seekers and Employers to find each other in Australia and New Zealand. FOSSLR is changing the way job seekers and employers seek and recruit. FOSSLR is a new approach to the current cumbersome and unrewarding job and candidate search tools.

ASP.NET MVC 4.0 | Window Azure | Generic Repository

5. Property Digg (Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services)

A home and real estate portal for all stakeholders; buyers, sellers, renters, brokers, insurance, etc.

ASP.NET MVC | C#.NET | MS SQL 2012 | Entity Framework | Generic Repository

6. BCAS (Hi-Tech Outsourcing Services)

BCAS is a name for the project developed for HAKs team, which is conducting an inspection of Assets and Structure of overall Schools across the specified Cities. They wanted to build an online system to ensure quick execution of their process.

ASP.NET MVC | MS SQL 2008 R2 | JavaScript | JQuery

7. **Verve Internal System** (Verve System Private Limited)

VIS includes attendance module, leave module, worksheet module, interview management, appraisal of the employee, the skill of employee, business development module, contact management and finance module.

ASP.NET 4.0 | C# Net | MS SQL 2008 R2 | JavaScript | JQuery | WCF

8. VIS - Google Chrome Extension (Verve System Private Limited)

VIS Extension is the simple google chrome extension for VIS contact management. It includes searching data in VIS and inserts data to VIS using WCF Service.

JavaScript | JSON | WCF

9. 4eDental and 4eDental University (Verve System Private Limited)

4eDental makes it possible for a clinical assistant to track every detail related to the treatments, appointments and fees paid for the treatments. 4eDental University is the basis of Learning dental courses and treatment of dental surgery and education.

ASP.NET 4.0(C#) | SQL Server 2008 R2 | JavaScript | JQuery | WCF Service | Silverlight 5.0

Education and Qualifications

2007 – 2011 Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering

Government Engineering College, Modasa, Gujarat

2006 - 2007 Higher Secondary Certificate

Gujarat State Higher Secondary Board, Gujarat

2004 – 2005 Secondary School Certificates

Gujarat State Education Board, Gujarat

Personal Details

Languages English, Hindi, Gujarati Date of Birth 25th Nov 1989

Marital Status Married Hobby Travelling and Sports

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information of this resume is correct as best of my knowledge and belief. Hope I will get a chance to serve under your kind control. I assure you sir that I shall do my best to the entire satisfaction of my superiors.

Place: Ahmedabad Rakesh Jogani